[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b260", "question": "What did the US Federal Reserve system do a record seventeen consecutive times between 2004 and 2006?", "answer": "Raise interest rates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c4a", "question": "According to poet Carl Sandburg, what \"creeps in on little cat feet\"?", "answer": "The fog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062cc2c9d816e292245c2e", "question": "To which artistic movement does Paul Gauguin's The Yellow Christ belong?", "answer": "The Yellow Christ\u00a0is a painting that depicts the crucifixion. The techniques used in this painting are typical of\u00a0cloisonnism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac8", "question": "The folklore characters known as \"oni\" originated in which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d3", "question": "Which famous actor voiced characters Lovelace and Ramon in the movie \"Happy Feet\"?", "answer": "Robin Williams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007810cbd51d85e222ab647", "question": "What art movement literally means the style of \"the wild beasts\"?", "answer": "Fauvism\u00a0(The movement emphasized vivid expressionism and unnatural use of color over representational or realistic values.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b967", "question": "How many ballet dancers would you find dancing a \u2018pas de deux\u2019?", "answer": "2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a095", "question": "What was the name of Punky Brewster's dog?", "answer": "Brandon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f3c7fa5fdd6dd25324dc", "question": "What's the principal river of Ireland?", "answer": "Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af983c3aeb0982ee4559549", "question": "In the movie \"Star Wars: Episode VII - The Force Awakens\", who kills Han Solo?", "answer": "Kylo Ren", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339220", "question": "Who were the principal members of the band \"The Beatles\"?", "answer": "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, George Harrison, Ringo Starr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdffc9f1cf6db9ac4808d01", "question": "What is the smallest country located entirely within the Himalayas?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b4be01dd7bf43be5e7c6", "question": "Why were bowler hats invented?", "answer": "To protect gamekeepers from low branches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ffa", "question": "What was poured on anyone who said \"I don't know\" on \"You Can't DO That on Television\"?", "answer": "Green slime", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab43", "question": "Vienna is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd3bcec223966ae8f88c8", "question": "In what movie does Gloria Swanson say, \"All right, Mr. DeMille, I'm ready for my close-up\"?", "answer": "\"Sunset Boulevard\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a315", "question": "Who played the role of Samantha Jones on the TV show \"Sex and the City\"?", "answer": "Kim Cattrall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f5", "question": "In what U.S. City was the Rag\u00fa brand of Italian-style sauces first produced?", "answer": "Rochester, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b30", "question": "In \"Dumb & Dumber\", to give back a misplaced briefcase, Harry and Lloyd travel to what US city?", "answer": "Aspen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cc5c877e98cb97778a23", "question": "Which city was the first capital of Japan?", "answer": "Nara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc4", "question": "The majority of the World's real cinnamon comes from what island nation?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a047", "question": "What song was Hawaiin Don Ho most known for?", "answer": "Tiny Bubbles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae94f4574a5ce6b56b824d", "question": "Which African country is Lilongwe the capital of?", "answer": "Malawi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a25f0d26682715b82711cda", "question": "What does the saying \"Requiescat in pace\" abbreviate to?", "answer": "RIP", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad74", "question": "Early American colonists boiled blueberries in milk to make what?", "answer": "Gray paint", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db7", "question": "The Siege Perilous was the name for the empty seat where?", "answer": "The Round Table", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c838", "question": "Bauxite ore is mined so it can be processed into what metal?", "answer": "Aluminum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa400bc73aa70ea0b70b06", "question": "The Pine Barrens in southern New Jersey is the supposed home of which legendary creature?", "answer": "Jersey Devil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b504", "question": "What are A.C. Milan, Ajax and Real Madrid?", "answer": "Soccer clubs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b2de4fda37788a9a1dbe", "question": "Who directed the 1962 film \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "David Lean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b693", "question": "Until 2008, what color was the center square on a standard Scrabble board?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a5ba90aac110e4167075", "question": "What does a Tegestologist collect?", "answer": "Beer coasters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7bb", "question": "What is measured in Amperes?", "answer": "Electric current", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18d", "question": "What is the name of the oscar winning actor who is the spokesperson for Farmer's Insurance?", "answer": "J.K. Simmons", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c33d", "question": "How many furlongs to a mile?", "answer": "8", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b174565bb2d29f81593b701", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the British-American rock band \"Foreigner\"?", "answer": "Lou Gramm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a436", "question": "Is Japan closer to the North Pole or the South Pole?", "answer": "North Pole", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca32", "question": "What is a group of lions called?", "answer": "Pride", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cb70c30f96e155acab35d29", "question": "How much did the United States pay Russia per acre for the purchase of Alaska in 1867?", "answer": "About 2 Cents per acre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca8", "question": "What kind of fur coat does Cruella De Vil covet?", "answer": "Dalmatian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948c", "question": "In the movie \"Days of Thunder\", what car is Cole told to hit in his first race?", "answer": "The pace car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5724c73aa70ea0b70b31", "question": "The May Day Run, held annually in England, involves thousands of what?", "answer": "Motorbikes taking the 55-mile trek from Locksbottom to Hastings.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bb35ac72627b8fe95581be9", "question": "In what country was Mel Gibson born?", "answer": "United States", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4f", "question": "Little Red Riding Hood was called what in the original story by the Brothers Grimm?", "answer": "Little Red Cap", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bfe0020b668d7dfe168b5bf", "question": "Which brand of beer does Homer Simpson drink regularly?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b143", "question": "Who was the first US President to be impeached by the US House of Representatives?", "answer": "Andrew Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f0a1ff048f679a45aaa1", "question": "Scoptophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Being stared at", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b801", "question": "How old is a Jewish boy who has a bar mitzvah?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede3b36ce05a3942286dd5", "question": "In what hotel does Ben rendezvous with Mrs. Robinson in \"The Graduate\"?", "answer": "The Taft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6d", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"The Miracle Worker\"?", "answer": "Patty Duke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b838e662d71a5365101f", "question": "In \"Pinocchio\", what are all the bad boys on Pleasure Island changed into?", "answer": "Donkeys", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062d9ac9d816e292245c35", "question": "Who painted \"The Scream\"?", "answer": "Edvard Munch\u00a0painted \"The Scream.\"  His style is recognized by most critics as leading to the birth of German Expressionism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72ce4cd0874f1a5e2d1c27", "question": "Which prominent US statesman was known as \"The Great Compromiser\" and helped allegedly swing the 1824 election?", "answer": "Henry Clay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f757fe83fe1f2a824c20", "question": "Which U.S. President worked as a tailor and made his own suits?", "answer": "Before he became President, Andrew Johnson worked as a tailor in Greeneville, Tennessee.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f9", "question": "What Ridley Scott movie features Tom Cruise trying to save the last unicorn?", "answer": "Legend", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe938516bd93ce3a4e5f683", "question": "Koinoniphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Rooms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b323608bf195a31e15d73b5", "question": "What character was invented to respond to questions from Gold Medal Flour customers?", "answer": "Betty Crocker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a238", "question": "What studio album did the band Men at Work release in 1981?", "answer": "Business as Usual", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf7", "question": "The feet of the infamous Pez dispenser were not added until what year?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd4bc7e83c707845b215f", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku Period", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a7ef6c0f9723ab15cb60", "question": "What is the longest someone has gone without sleeping?", "answer": "266 hours", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59d1855f3b17032616b590fd", "question": "What year was instant coffee was first patented in France?", "answer": "1881", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a862", "question": "The popular tourist destination, Amalfi, is located in which Italian region?", "answer": "Campania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca9e", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Sodium?", "answer": "Na", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82e", "question": "What does the abbreviation NASCAR stand for?", "answer": "National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a401", "question": "Which city is the Dutch parliament in?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ff43fe83fe1f2a824c4c", "question": "Why did US President Theodore Roosevelt ban Christmas trees in the White House in 1901?", "answer": "He banned the trees during his first year in office due to him being \"a devoted environmentalist\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c347", "question": "What is the name of the test to determine whether a computer could convincingly imitate a human?", "answer": "The Turing test", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8601ec223966ae8f880c", "question": "\"City of God\" takes place in which Third World city?", "answer": "The slums of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5c5", "question": "What is the official state animal of the US state of Oregon?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a476", "question": "What African country was formerly known as Northern Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015eac4fe83fe1f2a824bf4", "question": "What does the color white represent in the American flag?", "answer": "White symbolizes purity and innocence.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c596877e98cb977789b2", "question": "What marks the border between Asia and Africa?", "answer": "Suez Canal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c486", "question": "What is secured in a ship's cathead?", "answer": "The anchor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff51cecff04d658268c931f", "question": "What famous general was once attacked by rabbits?", "answer": "Napoleon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aabb", "question": "In what modern-day country did the Sabines live?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf2", "question": "When did the Hindenburg airship disaster occur?", "answer": "1937", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c9", "question": "Who was the last European head of state to be executed after being removed from power?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1f1cb145fb29466707394", "question": "What British automobile company made a car called the Super Snipe?", "answer": "Humber", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b5", "question": "Death Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb5cbd5dad637d903c881f", "question": "What is the official State fruit of New York?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aca4", "question": "Which American inventor held 1,093 patents?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339026", "question": "Who famously said \"When in doubt tell the truth.\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c352877e98cb97778994", "question": "Which U.S. state is famous for its bluebonnets?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbb", "question": "Which sea is located between Australia and New Zealand?", "answer": "Tasman Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79a", "question": "What year was the planet Neptune first discovered?", "answer": "1846", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ed", "question": "What are the four largest islands in Canada?", "answer": "Baffin, Victoria, Ellesmere and Newfoundland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f30", "question": "What literary locale is called \"Manor Farm\" at the start of the novel?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f716ea9e54d890926f6e0", "question": "In which country is the Troi-Rivieres bridge?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39b", "question": "What is James Naismith best known for?", "answer": "Inventing Basketball", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d118f64fea7fe947a2228a", "question": "An adventurous penguin Tennessee Tuxedo had a sidekick named what?", "answer": "Chumley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08c", "question": "What was the nickname of American frontiersman Christopher Houston Carson?", "answer": "Kit", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c9", "question": "In 1989, several hundred Chinese students were killed while demonstrating in what Beijing location?", "answer": "Tiananmen Square", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ee", "question": "What US state has been led by William McKinley and Salmon P. Chase?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6f2", "question": "What device was Alexander Graham Bell working, which led him to the invention of the telephone?", "answer": "Hearing aid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c638", "question": "What is the worlds fastest growing plant?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f32", "question": "What is the infirmity of Jake Barnes, the protagonist of \"The Sun Also Rises\"?", "answer": "He's impotent from a war wound", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c781fbde8045e48466c3", "question": "What was the first masculine name given to a hurricane?", "answer": "Bob", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a13a", "question": "In the TV series \"The Fall Guy\", who did Lee Majors play?", "answer": "Colt Seavers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d8", "question": "In what year did Michelangelo finish painting the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "1512", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c69f", "question": "Approximately how many light years is the North Star from Earth?", "answer": "434", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b600", "question": "What US state was the home of General Motors' original \"Saturn\" automobile plant?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a7f51a6f5f79087132fb3d", "question": "What do British people call zucchini?", "answer": "Courgette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b650", "question": "What con man made millions in the 1920s using a pyramid scheme?", "answer": "Carlo Ponzi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d0", "question": "How many guns does Travis buy in the movie \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "4", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b9", "question": "Who tore up a picture of the Pope on US television in 1992?", "answer": "Sinead O'Connor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29a", "question": "What US politician was named for Julius Caesar?", "answer": "J. C. Watts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed0", "question": "Before he turned to acting, what was Marky Mark's only number one song?", "answer": "Good Vibrations", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2d", "question": "What was Mark Twain's real name?", "answer": "Samuel Clemens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a4", "question": "The Sam Maguire Cup is played for in which sport?", "answer": "Gaelic Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a63b90aac110e416707c", "question": "What fruit oil is added to tea to create Earl Grey tea?", "answer": "Bergamot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a030", "question": "Who voices the character of Glenn Quagmire in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Seth MacFarlane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e5", "question": "Who directed the film \"Serpico\"?", "answer": "Sidney Lumet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3db", "question": "What year did poet Sylvia Plath end her life?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339202", "question": "What do Brad Pitt and Edward Norton shoot at factories while drunk in \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "Golf Balls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b57", "question": "Which movie studio has a roaring lion as its logo?", "answer": "MGM", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db76b80ab2c8f322317fe6", "question": "What was the gang name of John Travolta and his cohorts in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The T-Birds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d6", "question": "What is a fruit machine?", "answer": "A slot machine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a8", "question": "\"Sphenopalatine Ganglioneuralgia\" is commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Brain freeze", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea45dcff048f679a45ab9a", "question": "What is a Canis Lupus?", "answer": "Gray Wolf", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdffaf31cf6db9ac4808cf2", "question": "Which was the last contiguous U.S. territory to obtain statehood?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babb", "question": "What was the combined points scored in Super Bowl II?", "answer": "47", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfd", "question": "Whose famous balloon says \"State Fair Omaha\" on the outside?", "answer": "The Wizard of Oz's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c36d", "question": "What valuable product is obtained from the sturgeon?", "answer": "Caviar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc3edec223966ae8f8882", "question": "Which player graced the cover of the videogame \"Madden NFL 17\"?", "answer": "Rob Gronkowski", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ad", "question": "Who recorded the international hit single \"Poker Face\" in 2008?", "answer": "Lady Gaga", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d4", "question": "In the song where was \"The House of the Rising Sun\" located?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c200", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games in 1896?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3235f5bf195a31e15d73b4", "question": "Who played the electric piano on the Beatles track \"Get Back\"?", "answer": "Billy Preston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a792", "question": "Trinidad and Tobago is part of which continent?", "answer": "North America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b85", "question": "What\u2019s the ballet term for a 360 degree turn on one foot?", "answer": "A Pirouette", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb0", "question": "What modern-day conglomerate built Zero fighter planes used to bomb Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "Mitsubishi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b5a101dd7bf43be5e7d3", "question": "What is the term for the space between your eyebrows?", "answer": "Glabella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b6", "question": "Which movie popularized the phrase \"You had me at hello.\"?", "answer": "Jerry Maguire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96f97ccba3ffe45786f5", "question": "A 1 to 3 mph wind on the Beaufort scale is called what?", "answer": "Light air", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab7", "question": "On Mount Rushmore, which one of the presidents is wearing a jacket?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d83", "question": "Whose posthumous albums include \"R U Still Down?\", \"Still I Rise\", and \"Until the End of Time\"?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908f", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Eirene?", "answer": "Pax", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a76690aac110e4167086", "question": "What was the original purpose of tea bags in the western world?", "answer": "To store small samples of tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ad", "question": "Who played the teenage prostitute in the 1976 film \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e9", "question": "On what video game platform did the Gran Turismo game series debut?", "answer": "Playstation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a7c220565ad31a57c7ee", "question": "Where was paper first produced?", "answer": "China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9a2", "question": "What does the military term AWOL stand for?", "answer": "Absent Without Official Leave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049c77cf93664eb10486a7", "question": "At most, how many Friday the 13th can there be in the same calendar year?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc6e", "question": "Who developed the processed cheese spread known as Cheez Whiz?", "answer": "Edwin Traisman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf9", "question": "What was the first building in the world to have more than 100 floors?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f2", "question": "In The Simpsons, what colour is Ralph's belt buckle?", "answer": "Red", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf64", "question": "George Fox founded which religious group?", "answer": "Quakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e0", "question": "What fruit comes in Eureka and Meyer variety?", "answer": "Lemons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c7", "question": "What year did Suriname gain its independence from the Kingdom of the Netherlands?", "answer": "1975", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feba95a7e83c707845b20d5", "question": "Which astronomical celestial event generally occurs on the same date as the International Day of Happiness?", "answer": "March Equinox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b34901dd7bf43be5e7ab", "question": "What store was originally called \"Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Best Buy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f191ff048f679a45aab2", "question": "Is it the female or the male turkey that gobbles?", "answer": "The male gobbles and the female cackles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c7", "question": "A silk-screened print is also known as what?", "answer": "Serigraph", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26e", "question": "Who won an Oscar as Best Supporting actor in the 1993 film \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c507", "question": "What sensory organ do starfish have at the end of each arm?", "answer": "Eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b431", "question": "Which country saw the Mau Mau Uprising?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7caa1877e98cb97778a08", "question": "In which country will you find the cities Toledo and Granada?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338970", "question": "What century did Rembrandt live in?", "answer": "17th", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab2", "question": "What actress played Phoebe's mother on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Teri Garr", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8b", "question": "What rock musician is known as \"The Motor City Madman\"?", "answer": "Ted Nugent", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8a6", "question": "What European nation still pledges its allegiance to a foreign monarch in its national anthem?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4e2fd06d333868d34d72b", "question": "Which conflict ended with the \"Good Friday Agreement\"?", "answer": "The Troubles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e24", "question": "What kind of dinosaur is the Flintstones' Dino?", "answer": "A snorkasaurus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338909", "question": "Who wrote \"The Hunchback of Notre Dame\"?", "answer": "Victor Hugo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5902a1becad1ec93f27df779", "question": "In the beer world, what does the abbreviation IBU stand for?", "answer": "International Bitterness Units", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d28", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Lords of Dogtown\"?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a4", "question": "What is poliosis?", "answer": "Graying of hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab98", "question": "What Australian state shares a nickname with the US state of Florida?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339530", "question": "What show begins with the line \"In a time of ancient gods, warlords and kings...\"?", "answer": "Xena: Warrior Princess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfe006ab668d7dfe168b5c2", "question": "What metal impurity makes rubies red and emeralds green?", "answer": "Chromium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb0", "question": "Which was the first country to leave the Commonwealth in 1949?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a283", "question": "Queen provided the soundtrack to which 1980 space opera starring Max von Sydow and Brian Blessed?", "answer": "Flash Gordon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3c2364f032c0db195b47f", "question": "What did ancient Egyptians use as pillows?", "answer": "Wooden or stone headrests", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c1620775fa611bce67c3", "question": "Dysmorphia is a mental disorder characterized by what?", "answer": "The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed. The obsessive idea that some aspect of one's own body part or appearance is severely flawed, and therefore, warrants exceptional measures to hide or fix it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b86e", "question": "What is the point value of the outer bull's eye on the dartboard?", "answer": "25 points", "category": "general"}, {"id": "590683dfff9c0647b50a80ab", "question": "Which album won the 2016 Grammy Award for \"Album of the Year\"?", "answer": "1989", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8c4", "question": "What is the more common name for Eponychium?", "answer": "Cuticle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c743", "question": "What is the more common term for amblyopia?", "answer": "Lazy eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febad607e83c707845b20f2", "question": "What is the longest muscle in the human body?", "answer": "Sartorius", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a940", "question": "What river's waterfalls led to the naming of the Cascade Range?", "answer": "The Columbia's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93f", "question": "What country is home to Angel Falls?", "answer": "Venezuela", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70b", "question": "Which three states share a border with California?", "answer": "Arizona, Nevada and Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c09", "question": "What year was Anna Nicole Smith selected as a Playboy Playmate of the Year?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e6", "question": "What year was the Amazon Kindle Fire first introduced?", "answer": "2011", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7701deec85e375820b2f5", "question": "What is the highest elevation capital city in Asia?", "answer": "Thimphu, Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cc", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cf", "question": "Fred Schneider was a member of which famous band?", "answer": "The B-52's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f0", "question": "What must a Las Vegas blackjack dealer do when they reaches 16?", "answer": "Take a card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f1cb01dd7bf43be5e808", "question": "Which Crayola color did consumers vote to save from retirement in 2003?", "answer": "Burnt sienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c99b", "question": "By what more common name is the star cluster, Pleiades, better known as?", "answer": "Seven Sisters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f74dfa9e54d890926f701", "question": "According to Russian law, a homeless person must be where after 10 pm?", "answer": "At home", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df1", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"pariah\"?", "answer": "Tamil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bef49076251badbeaca", "question": "Which U.S. President had his sister initially serve as First Lady?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland -- \u00a0His sister Rose Cleveland took on the duties of First Lady until he married his bride Frances in June 1886.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a654", "question": "The shoreline of which US state is broken by Albemarle Sound?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339267", "question": "What is the name of the coolest girls' gang in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The Pink Ladies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bad", "question": "How many nights are there in \"Arabian Nights\"?", "answer": "1001", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898c", "question": "What snack gave Mickey Mouse his first spoken words?", "answer": "Hot dogs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae70", "question": "What US first lady was nicknamed \"the Silver Fox\"?", "answer": "Barbara Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff145cab0ee8c595b6d39bb", "question": "Richard Bachman is a pen name used by which American author?", "answer": "Steven King", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339167", "question": "What is Mickey Mouse's dog's name?", "answer": "Pluto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f89f01dd7bf43be5e845", "question": "The Gray Lady refers to which newspaper?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dfb1dcf3977a46e7ce449", "question": "There are 293 ways to make change for a what?", "answer": "Dollar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c94a", "question": "What is the fear of getting wrinkles known as?", "answer": "Rhytiphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c2c54f032c0db195b485", "question": "In 1912, what did a Paris orphanage give away as prizes when it held a raffle to raise money?", "answer": "Live babies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae95a3574a5ce6b56b8257", "question": "What are formed by Orogeny?", "answer": "Mountains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b9", "question": "Who wrote and also starred in the 1980 movie \"The Blues Brothers\"?", "answer": "Dan Aykroyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fb1c06af497e33de805791c", "question": "What baseball announcer was famous for this signature phrase: \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2b", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"Youngblood\"?", "answer": "Ice hockey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9ba40364247bf200fb896", "question": "Which two demons aid Satan in Milton's \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "Beelzebub and Mammon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6000f14a9a72b906b34e3d03", "question": "What kind of animal is a bantam?", "answer": "Chicken -- A true bantam is a breed of chicken that is naturally small.  The male has a reputation for being very aggressive.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3d", "question": "What slogan did Nancy Reagan create for her drug awareness campaign?", "answer": "Just Say No", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323700bf195a31e15d73c1", "question": "Which supermodel is nicknamed \"The Body\"?", "answer": "Elle Macpherson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0b", "question": "How many tiles does a player play to score a bingo in Scrabble?", "answer": "7", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f4", "question": "Who had a hit with the song and album \"Sweet Dreams (Are Made Of This)\"?", "answer": "Eurythmics", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d3", "question": "What famous American was nicknamed \"The Lone Eagle\"?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea46c3ff048f679a45aba5", "question": "The diameter of an atom is measured in which units?", "answer": "Angstroms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aace", "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?", "answer": "Brasilia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb3", "question": "Robert Plant was the lead singer for what rock band from 1968 to 1980?", "answer": "Led Zeppelin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60173b9e44491cbd7c5a179f", "question": "What era marked the beginning of farming?", "answer": "The Stone Age -- The ability for tribes to maintain farming brought with it settlements and domestication of animals.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fbae8090738315b1fb74e27", "question": "What mathematician published more papers in his lifetime than any other mathematician in history?", "answer": "Paul Erdos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5cefc19f948005ec986edce7", "question": "What powers Iron Man's suit?", "answer": "Arc reactor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aadf", "question": "Which country does Egypt border to the south?", "answer": "Sudan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59523e1d736d4be723796b4b", "question": "In which Canadian city would you find the largest mall in North America?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff13b668d7dfe168b5b4", "question": "In which country is the alcoholic drink Pulque consumed?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79e", "question": "How many moons does the planet Neptune have?", "answer": "14", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934e", "question": "Who played Alex's sister, Mallory, on the TV show \"Family Ties\"?", "answer": "Justine Bateman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c353", "question": "Mn is the chemical symbol for which element?", "answer": "Manganese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b04a", "question": "What is \"Dan\" short for in former US vice\u00ad president Dan Quayle's name?", "answer": "Danforth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a02d6c0f9723ab15cb34", "question": "How many electoral college votes does a U.S. presidential candidate need to get elected?", "answer": "270", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396b3", "question": "What Scottish hero did Mel Gibson portray in the 1995 movie \"Braveheart\"?", "answer": "William Wallace", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077f38bd51d85e222ab63c", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism (An example is where barnacles live on some whales and benefit by having a place to live and feed, while the whale is not harmed, but derives no benefit.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8cc", "question": "What chain opened its first store in 1962 in the town of Rogers, Arkansas?", "answer": "Wal-Mart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ca", "question": "Who presented the radio programme \"In the Psychiatrist's Chair\"?", "answer": "Anthony Clare", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4a", "question": "Who was the first US president to be assassinated?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a85b", "question": "On which harbour is the Sydney Opera House located?", "answer": "Sydney Harbour", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac56", "question": "What landlocked European country remained neutral in both World Ware I and World War II?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9335574a5ce6b56b8237", "question": "Juventas was the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Youth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5937ebdb08d98002fdd633b3", "question": "The study of human behaviour and mind is called what?", "answer": "Psychology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e2", "question": "How did Buffalo Bill die?", "answer": "Kidney failure", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062b3dc9d816e292245c1f", "question": "In which Massachusetts town is \"Little Women\" set?", "answer": "Louisa May Alcott\u2019s semi-autobiographical work takes place in Concord, Massachusetts, where she and her three sisters lived.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523c05736d4be723796b34", "question": "On what day does Canada celebrate its birthday?", "answer": "July 1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc5cbec223966ae8f8883", "question": "Bruce Willis played a convict turned time traveler in what 1995 movie?", "answer": "\"12 Monkeys\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3eb0d38e4e5d4832e6318", "question": "What name was given to the west wind by the Greeks?", "answer": "Zephyrus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e70006d333868d34d738", "question": "How many specific commandments regulating aspects of people's lives are there in the Bible in the Mosaic Law?", "answer": "613", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff511c7ff04d658268c92ca", "question": "How did Mary Ludwig Hays earn the nickname \"Molly Pitcher\"?", "answer": "During the Battle of Monmouth, she attended to the Revolutionary soldiers by\u00a0bringing them water, often under heavy fire.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1c", "question": "What author created the land of Poictesme?", "answer": "James Branch Cabell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c3f", "question": "What duo composed the operetta \"Porgy and Bess\"?", "answer": "George Gershwin and Ira Gershwin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b9b", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Rights of Man\"?", "answer": "Thomas Paine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d06ad1a1c922dd1ac64ae", "question": "What's the official state sport of Alaska?", "answer": "Dog mushing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3985ff048f679a45ab28", "question": "What is the smallest organ in the human body?", "answer": "Pineal gland", "category": "science"}]